SABUHI TEYMUROV

+994(77)-740-16-00 \diamond Sumgayit, Azerbaijan

hello@sabuhiteymurov.com ♦ linkedin.com/in/sabuhi-teymurov ♦ www.sabuhiteymurov.com

OBJECTIVE

Results-driven software developer with 2+ years of experience developing and maintaining software applications. Driven to continuously improve my technical skills and eager to work on challenging projects that will help me expand my skill set.

SKILLS

Languages Javascript, Typescript

Frameworks and Technologies React, Next.js, React native, Redux, Node.js, NextAuth.js, Socket.IO,

RTK Query, OAuth, MongoDB, Sass, Jest, Docker

Soft Skills Adaptability, Collaboration, Communication, Time management, Empathy

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Ferrum Capital

Aug 2022 - Present Baku, Azerbaijan

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including product management and design, to deliver high-quality and user-friendly software.
- Mentored junior developers and provided technical guidance, leading to improved performance and knowledge retention.
- Improved application performance by optimizing the codebase, reducing the number of re-renders through the utilization of libraries like react-hook-form. Additionally, caching techniques were implemented by incorporating technologies like React Query and RTK Query for further enhancing performance.
- Enhanced app performance by creating an infinite scrollable table capable of handling more than 200,000 data entries with the help of the tanstack/react-table, tanstack/react-virtual libraries and tanstack/react-query's useInfiniteQuery.
- Utilized React Native (Expo framework) to develop cross-functional native apps for Android and iOS platforms.

Junior Front-End Developer

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

Freelancer.com

Remote

- Collaborated with clients to oversee the production and maintenance of website and web application interfaces, and developed reusable code for future use.
- Ensured that the front end of the websites was error-free and bug-free.

PROJECTS

Kalee - Appointment Scheduling App Kalee is a software application designed to help individuals manage their appointments and schedules. It provides a convenient way to schedule and book appointments online, eliminating the need for manual appointment scheduling. Over 1000 people have used it so far, with 5000+ meetings being scheduled! (Project link)

- Led the project's front end, which included the development and implementation of the app from scratch.
- Implemented a real-time appointment booking system with the help of the Socket.IO client, enabling users to view available times.
- Integrated and prepared the app for verification on Google Meets, Zoom, and Microsoft Teams platforms. Implemented authentication and authorization for the app (sign-in/sign-up/JWT refresh token strategy) using technologies such as Axios interceptors and the NextAuth.js library.

Ferrum Capital Corporate Website The main technologies utilized were jQuery, CSS, and Laravel blade templates. API integration and validation across the entire website. The website is regularly tested with Google Lighthouse for usability, speed, and other quality factors. Ensured the website is accessible across many platforms, including devices using older versions of macOS and iOS. (Project link)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Management, Azerbaijan Tourism and Management University

2017 - 2021